[
 {
   "question": "This question is based on George Orwell's 1984.\n\n\n'Big Brothers Is Watching You' Big Brother Controls life in Oceania Though the four ministries of peace, Love, plenty, are Truth.\n\nThe Couple continue to meet secretly in an attic room above a junk shop owned by",
   "option_a": "Mr. Carrington",
   "option_b": "O'Brien",
   "option_c": "Eurasia",
   "option_d": "Coworker Julius",
   "answer": "A",
   "solution": " Mr. Charrington, was the man who sold the diary, and later a coral paperweight to Winston."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on Buchi Emecheta's The Joys of Motherhood.\n\n\nNnaife and Nnu Ego Second Child but the first to live is",
   "option_a": "Adim",
   "option_b": "Ngozi",
   "option_c": "Oshia",
   "option_d": "Adaku",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": " In the novel, the death of the first child \"Ngozi led to Nnu Ego's committing suicide at the waterfront to Cater Bridge. The second child is therefore called Oshia, who belongs to Nnaife."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on William Shakespeare’s Romeo and Juliet.\n\n\nIn Romeo and Juliet, use the excerpt below to answer question 14 and 15.\n\n'.... So tedious is this day\n\nAs is the night before some festival\n\nTo an important child that hath them.\n\nnew robes and may not wear.\n\nThe literary device used in the excerpt is",
   "option_a": "simile",
   "option_b": "metaphor",
   "option_c": "Oxymoron",
   "option_d": "apostrophe",
   "answer": "A",
   "solution": "Simile is the comparison of two things using 'as' or 'like'. The simile in the excerpt is comparing 'this day as is the night before some festival'"
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on General literacy principles\n\n\nA literary genre which directly imitates human action is",
   "option_a": "drama",
   "option_b": "comedy",
   "option_c": "prose",
   "option_d": "poetry",
   "answer": "A",
   "solution": "Drama is happenings written in form of scripts that are not narrated but acted out on stage, television or radio by cast to the audience"
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on selected poems from Johnson, R. et ai (eds): New Poetry African: Soyinka W. (ed): Poems of Black Africa; Senanu, K.E. and Vincent. T. (eds): A Selection of African Poetry, U. Maduka, C. T et al: Exam Focus: Literature in English: Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds): Longman Examination Guides: Nwoga D. I. (ed): West African verse and Adeoti G: Naked Soles.\n\nThe excerpt below from Marvell's To His Coy Mistress is an example of\n\n\nIn Houseman's To an Athlete Dying Young, the persona addresses the dead athlete using",
   "option_a": "Monologue",
   "option_b": "Dialogue",
   "option_c": "Apostrophe",
   "option_d": "Prologue",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Apostrophe is an address that is directed to an absent person as if the person is present. Therefore, the persona addresses the dead athlete as if the athlete is still present or alive."
 },
 {
   "question": "The use of two contrasting words that are placed side by side is called",
   "option_a": "prologue",
   "option_b": "oxymoron",
   "option_c": "apostrophe",
   "option_d": "costume",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": " Oxymoron is the placement of the two opposite words side by side."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on General literacy principles\n\n\nIn literacy work, verbal irony refers to a",
   "option_a": "device in which the speaker means the opposite of what he says",
   "option_b": "situation in which a character speaks or acts against the trends of events",
   "option_c": "difficult situation which defies a logical or national resolution",
   "option_d": "device in which the actor on stage means exactly what he says",
   "answer": "A",
   "solution": "Irony is the recognition of a reality different from its masking appearance. It is the \"reversal\" of meaning."
 },
 {
   "question": "A speech or writing used to praise a person or a thing for past or present deeds is",
   "option_a": "eulogy",
   "option_b": "synecdoche",
   "option_c": "epigram",
   "option_d": "epilogue",
   "answer": "A",
   "solution": "Eulogy is the word or writing used to praise a person or a thing for what had happened or what is happening."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on William Shakespeare’s Romeo and Juliet.\n\n\nRomeo is evicted to__________because he__________",
   "option_a": "Mantua, fights Tybalt in a street duel",
   "option_b": "Capulet's party, kills Tybalt in a street duel",
   "option_c": "Mantua, fights and kills Tybalt in a street duel",
   "option_d": "Mantua, kills Paris in a street duel.",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Romeo was expelled or banished to Mantua for killing Tybalt in a street combat."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on Buchi Emecheta's The Joys of Motherhood.\n\n\nThe relationships of Nnaife family are",
   "option_a": "humiliation and disagreement",
   "option_b": "sickness and joblessness",
   "option_c": "poverty and hunger",
   "option_d": "togetherness and happiness",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "In the novel, Nnaife lost his job. Nnu Ego struggled to feed the family. Nnaife's family was sent out of their previous apartment; Nnu Ego rented a small apartment and finally travelled to the village of Ogboli in Ibuza homeland where she ended her life."
 },
 {
   "question": "In drama, the use of gestures to communicate is known as",
   "option_a": "mime",
   "option_b": "realistic drama",
   "option_c": "melodrama",
   "option_d": "dialogue",
   "answer": "A",
   "solution": "Mime is the gesture without any speech to the audience."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on J.C. De Graft's Sons and Daughters\n\n\nA brother to Aaron and Maanan is",
   "option_a": "George",
   "option_b": "Awere",
   "option_c": "Hannah",
   "option_d": "Awao",
   "answer": "A",
   "solution": "This is found on the third page of the book, where all characters and their roles in the play are written."
 },
 {
   "question": "A significant of a whole through its significant part is",
   "option_a": "allegory",
   "option_b": "pun",
   "option_c": "synecdoche",
   "option_d": "cast",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Synecdoche is an expression that uses part of a thing to represent a whole or a whole to represent a part."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on Literary Appreciation.\n\n\nA cursing rogue with a merry farce,\n\nA bundle of rags upon a crurch,\n\nStumbled upon that windy place\n\nCalled cruachan, and it was as much.\n\nThe rhyme scheme of the stanza above is",
   "option_a": "aabb",
   "option_b": "abab",
   "option_c": "bbaa",
   "option_d": "abba",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": ""
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on selected poems from Johnson, R. et ai (eds): New Poetry African: Soyinka W. (ed): Poems of Black Africa; Senanu, K.E. and Vincent. T. (eds): A Selection of African Poetry, U. Maduka, C. T et al: Exam Focus: Literature in English: Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds): Longman Examination Guides: Nwoga D. I. (ed): West African verse and Adeoti G: Naked Soles.\n\nThe excerpt below from Marvell's To His Coy Mistress is an example of\n\n\nIn Launko's End of the War, the Casualties are",
   "option_a": "women",
   "option_b": "soldiers",
   "option_c": "children",
   "option_d": "men",
   "answer": "D",
   "solution": "The casualties discovered in Launko's End of the War were men."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on Literary Appreciation.\n\n\nThe imagery created in the excerpt below is achieved through\n\n'........They do not see the funeral piles\n\nAt home eating up the forests.......'\n\n_ _ J.P. -Clark: Casualties",
   "option_a": "metaphor",
   "option_b": "personification",
   "option_c": "synecdoche",
   "option_d": "antonym",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Personification is the idea that represents a thing, an object, or abstract idea as though it were a living being."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on selected poems from Johnson, R. et ai (eds): New Poetry African: Soyinka W. (ed): Poems of Black Africa; Senanu, K.E. and Vincent. T. (eds): A Selection of African Poetry, U. Maduka, C. T et al: Exam Focus: Literature in English: Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds): Longman Examination Guides: Nwoga D. I. (ed): West African verse and Adeoti G: Naked Soles.\n\nThe excerpt below from Marvell's To His Coy Mistress is an example of\n\n\nThe figure of speech in the line below from Acquah's In the Navel of the Soul is 'We would be believing we dreamt it'",
   "option_a": "assonance",
   "option_b": "antithesis",
   "option_c": "apostrophe",
   "option_d": "alliteration",
   "answer": "A",
   "solution": "Assonance is defined as the repetition of similar vowel sounds within lines. Therefore /i/ is the assonance."
 },
 {
   "question": "Use the passage below to answer this question.\n\n\n'But the towering earth was tired of sitting in one position.\n\nShe moved, suddenly, and the houses crumbled, the mountains\n\nheaved horribly, and the work of million years was lost'.\n\n\nThe subject matter of the passage is",
   "option_a": "earthquake",
   "option_b": "demolition",
   "option_c": "flood",
   "option_d": "storm",
   "answer": "A",
   "solution": "It is earthquake because earth is tired of remaining constant in a place, buildings and mountains begin to shift in a position."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on selected poems from Johnson, R. et ai (eds): New Poetry African: Soyinka W. (ed): Poems of Black Africa; Senanu, K.E. and Vincent. T. (eds): A Selection of African Poetry, U. Maduka, C. T et al: Exam Focus: Literature in English: Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds): Longman Examination Guides: Nwoga D. I. (ed): West African verse and Adeoti G: Naked Soles.\n\nThe excerpt below from Marvell's To His Coy Mistress is an example of\n\n\nThe theme of Cope's sonnet V11 is",
   "option_a": "adventure",
   "option_b": "isolation",
   "option_c": "contempt for literature",
   "option_d": "art of poetry",
   "answer": "A",
   "solution": "In Cope's Sonnet Vll the poem is all about adventure."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on J.C. De Graft's Sons and Daughters\n\n\nWhere does the play take place?",
   "option_a": "In George's place",
   "option_b": "In Ofosu's place",
   "option_c": "On the street",
   "option_d": "On the stage",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "The play took place in Ofosu's place because James Ofosu had allowed himself to be manipulated by Lawyer Bonu and seems to follow Lawyer Bonu's advice blindly."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on General literacy principles\n\n\nA literary work in which the characters and events are used as symbol is known as",
   "option_a": "characterization",
   "option_b": "allegory",
   "option_c": "metaphor",
   "option_d": "parallelism",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "An allegory is a work of art, such as a story or painting, in which the characters, images, and/or events act as symbols. The symbolism in an allegory can be interpreted to have a deeper meaning. An author may use allegory to illustrate a moral or spiritual truth, or political or historical situation.\n\nAllegory is an attempt through which abstract or symbol is used to portray evils and ills common in our society."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on Literary Appreciation.\n\n\nIn Williams Shakespeare: Twelfth Night\n\nI have said too much unto a heart of stone,\n\nAnd laid my honour too unchary on it',\n\nThere's something in me that\n\nreproves my fault. But such a headstrong potent fault it is That it but mocks reproof.'\n\nA heart of stone in the lines above is an example of",
   "option_a": "assonance",
   "option_b": "Metaphor",
   "option_c": "Litotes",
   "option_d": "antonym",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "A heart of stone in the excerpt is metaphor because it is a direct comparison without the use of 'as' or 'like'."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on Buchi Emecheta's The Joys of Motherhood.\n\n\nWhy did Nnaife blame Nnu Ego for all his problems",
   "option_a": "Because his daughter slapped him",
   "option_b": "Because his daughter disobeyed him by travelling to abroad",
   "option_c": "Because his daughter disobeyed him by moving with prostitutes",
   "option_d": "Because his daughter ran away with a Yoruba man.",
   "answer": "D",
   "solution": "I Kehinde, the daughter of Nnaife broke his father's (Nnaife) rules by running away with a Yoruba man, he assaulted the father of Kehinde's husband. Sent to prison, Nnaife therefore blamed Nnu Ego for all his problems."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on J.C. De Graft's Sons and Daughters\n\n\nPaternal aunt to Aaron and Maanan is",
   "option_a": "Fosuwa",
   "option_b": "Hannah",
   "option_c": "Mrs. Bonu",
   "option_d": "Adwao",
   "answer": "A",
   "solution": "This can easily be found at the beginning of the play where all the characters are listed."
 },
 {
   "question": "Plays are basically meant to be",
   "option_a": "presented on stage",
   "option_b": "presented in the aircraft",
   "option_c": "presented in an office",
   "option_d": "presented in the hospital",
   "answer": "A",
   "solution": "Play is associated to drama and a drama is a situation whereby happenings written in form of scripts are not narrated but acted on stage, television or radio by cast to the audience."
 },
 {
   "question": "Travelogue is a work of art written",
   "option_a": "by a famous playwright",
   "option_b": "before the death of the author",
   "option_c": "by an unpopular novelist",
   "option_d": "on a journey",
   "answer": "D",
   "solution": "Travelogue is associated to a journey"
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on selected poems from Johnson, R. et ai (eds): New Poetry African: Soyinka W. (ed): Poems of Black Africa; Senanu, K.E. and Vincent. T. (eds): A Selection of African Poetry, U. Maduka, C. T et al: Exam Focus: Literature in English: Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds): Longman Examination Guides: Nwoga D. I. (ed): West African verse and Adeoti G: Naked Soles.\n\nThe excerpt below from Marvell's To His Coy Mistress is an example of\n\n\n'As if men hung here unbloom,\n\nTheir mildewed buds of love like pollen\n\nLate caught, damp in a swollen...'\n\nThe sound devise in the stanza above from Kalu Uka's 'Earth to Earth is",
   "option_a": "Onomatopoeia",
   "option_b": "repetition",
   "option_c": "rhythm",
   "option_d": "rhyme",
   "answer": "D",
   "solution": "Rhyme is the similar sound at the end of each line of a poem. The rhyme of the poem above is indicated as /abb/."
 },
 {
   "question": "Sweet smile in time of snarl\n\ngives pride in spite of sneer\n\nsing, rid this world of despair\n\nand save, a snared heart from\n\ncascading stream of strife\n\nThe dominant rhetorical device in the excerpt above is",
   "option_a": "rhyme",
   "option_b": "alliteration",
   "option_c": "chiasmus",
   "option_d": "onomatopoeia",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": ""
 },
 {
   "question": "Narrative poem indicates that the poet is attempting to",
   "option_a": "preach a sermon",
   "option_b": "tell a story",
   "option_c": "summarize a story",
   "option_d": "describe a place",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "A poet is a person who writes poetry."
 },
 {
   "question": "The use of sound pattern to suggest meaning in poetry is",
   "option_a": "lyric",
   "option_b": "lullaby",
   "option_c": "mimic",
   "option_d": "rhythm",
   "answer": "D",
   "solution": "Rhythm is the frequency of a sound, sound pattern or sound flow of a poetry."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on selected poems from Johnson, R. et ai (eds): New Poetry African: Soyinka W. (ed): Poems of Black Africa; Senanu, K.E. and Vincent. T. (eds): A Selection of African Poetry, U. Maduka, C. T et al: Exam Focus: Literature in English: Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds): Longman Examination Guides: Nwoga D. I. (ed): West African verse and Adeoti G: Naked Soles.\n\nThe excerpt below from Marvell's To His Coy Mistress is an example of\n\n\nThe literacy devices used in the lines 'Pataki and Mustard flowers like blue and yellow eyes peep through the green grass' are________from Mohan Singh's 'A Village Girl'",
   "option_a": "alliteration and assonance",
   "option_b": "simile and irony",
   "option_c": "repetition and alliteration",
   "option_d": "rhyme and rhythm",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "The simile is Pataki and Mustard flowers like blue and yellow eyes, it compares Pataki flower and blue eyes; mustard flower and yellow eyes using 'like'. The irony is peeping through the green grass."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on Literary Appreciation.\n\n\nMove him into the sun\n\nGently its touch awoke him once,\n\nAt home, whispering of field unsown\n\nAlways it woke him even in France\n\nUntil this morning and this snow\n\nIf anything might rouse him now\n\nThis kind of old sun will know\n\nThink how it woke the seeds\n\nWoke, once, the clay of a cold star\n\nAre limbs, so dear achieved, are\n\nsides full nerved still warm too hard\n\nto stir was it, for this the clay grew\n\ntall? O what made fatuous sunbeams\n\ntoil to break earth's sleep at all.\n\nThe poem can be described as",
   "option_a": "a lyric",
   "option_b": "an epic",
   "option_c": "a sonnet",
   "option_d": "an elegy",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "An epic is a long and elaborated narrative poem. It has a very serious philosophical or historical perspective."
 },
 {
   "question": "In literary devices, pun deals with",
   "option_a": "placing words side by side",
   "option_b": "playing on words",
   "option_c": "arrangement of words placing two opposite phrases Answer",
   "option_d": "placing two opposite phrases",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Pun is the repetition of words with similar sound which has different meanings in the context in which they were used."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on Literary Appreciation.\n\n\nO! Ceremony, show me but thy worth what is thy soul of adoration.\n\nThe figure of speech in the lines above is",
   "option_a": "antithesis",
   "option_b": "apostrophe",
   "option_c": "personification",
   "option_d": "euphemism",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Apostrophe is an address directed to an absent person as if present. The apostrophe in the line above is the soul of adoration."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on William Shakespeare’s Romeo and Juliet.\n\n\nIn Romeo and Juliet, the major role of Mercutio is to",
   "option_a": "Count Paris in Praise of Juliet",
   "option_b": "annoy Tybalt",
   "option_c": "take another wife",
   "option_d": "serve as an assistance to Romeo",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Mercutio and Benvolio who were Romeo's friends were waiting on the street when Tybalt arrives with the intention of challenging/punishing Romeo for sneaking into the party. Mercutio aggressively jumps into Romeo and Tybalt issues and drew out his sword on Tybalt but Tybalt cuts Mercutio."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on Buchi Emecheta's The Joys of Motherhood.\n\n\nIn Nnaife's house, life became miserable to Nnu Ego by the news that",
   "option_a": "Nnaife's elder brother had died",
   "option_b": "Nnaife has inherited buildings and properties",
   "option_c": "Nnaife had lost Ngozi",
   "option_d": "Nnaife has inherited his brother's wives and children.",
   "answer": "D",
   "solution": "Nnu Ego was sad to share Nnaife's pitiful salary with Adaku and her children. Life became worst for Nnu Ego and continues to struggle for survival."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on Buchi Emecheta's The Joys of Motherhood.\n\n\nIn the novel, it is necessary that Ona has to leave her father's house because",
   "option_a": "of the safety of her child",
   "option_b": "of her love for Agbadi",
   "option_c": "her father is dead",
   "option_d": "that is the tradition",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "It is obvious that once Ona is married, she must leave her father's house except she gives birth to a boy. Unfortunately, she dies during childbirth."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on William Shakespeare’s Romeo and Juliet.\n\n\n__________decides that Juliet should marry a young man named Paris, who has been asking for her hand",
   "option_a": "Friar Laurence",
   "option_b": "Lord Capulet",
   "option_c": "Balthasar",
   "option_d": "Friar John",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": ""
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on Buchi Emecheta's The Joys of Motherhood.\n\n\nNnu Ego's Second Marriage as to Nnaife, a man who works in Lagos as the washer for",
   "option_a": "Nwakusor",
   "option_b": "Dr. and Mrs. Meers",
   "option_c": "Nwaeze",
   "option_d": "Ngozi",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Nnu Ego's first marriage was without a child, she therefore married Nnaife who washed for a white family, Dr. and Mrs. Meers."
 },
 {
   "question": "Ballad is meant to be",
   "option_a": "discussed",
   "option_b": "read",
   "option_c": "sung",
   "option_d": "acted",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Ballad can be seen as another form of narrative poem. It is written in short stanzas and formed by ordinary people who are not poets. It is meant to be sung. It tells simple stories of amusement, war, death, love and the supernatural."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on General literacy principles\n\n\nThe repetition of single words or phrases at the beginning of lines is",
   "option_a": "parallelism",
   "option_b": "assonance",
   "option_c": "alliteration",
   "option_d": "pun",
   "answer": "A",
   "solution": "The question is simply the definition of parallelism."
 },
 {
   "question": "The account of experiences of an individual during the course of a journey is known as",
   "option_a": "an epilogue",
   "option_b": "an autobiography",
   "option_c": "a travelogue",
   "option_d": "a prologue",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "A travelogue is the correct answer because travelogue has to do with a journey from one place to another."
 },
 {
   "question": "Read the extract below and this answer question.\n\n\nThe pattering rain was kicking up little explosions of\n\ndust in the glade. He heard the faint whisper of the stream\n\nas it stole across the land and disappeared into the bush.\n\nThe underline expression in line 3 is",
   "option_a": "litotes",
   "option_b": "personification",
   "option_c": "hyperbole",
   "option_d": "synecdoche",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Personification is the idea of representing a thing, an object, a quality, inanimate thing or abstract idea as though it were a living being. The expression in line 3 above used an abstract idea to represent a living being i.e. explosion of dust hearing the whisper of the stream"
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on Literary Appreciation.\n\n\nThe old man slept in his favorite chair\n\nThe wind ran its fingers through his hairs\n\nHe looked like a tree gone dry of sap\n\nAnd his hands were dry upon his lap\n\nThe rhyme scheme of the poet above is",
   "option_a": "bbaa",
   "option_b": "aabb",
   "option_c": "abab",
   "option_d": "baba",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "This question is to test students understanding of rhymes. It is the similarity in the sound of the last word on each of the poetry line."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on selected poems from Johnson, R. et ai (eds): New Poetry African: Soyinka W. (ed): Poems of Black Africa; Senanu, K.E. and Vincent. T. (eds): A Selection of African Poetry, U. Maduka, C. T et al: Exam Focus: Literature in English: Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds): Longman Examination Guides: Nwoga D. I. (ed): West African verse and Adeoti G: Naked Soles.\n\nThe excerpt below from Marvell's To His Coy Mistress is an example of\n\n\n'.... The youthful hue/sits on thy skin like a morning dew...'",
   "option_a": "Onomatopoeia",
   "option_b": "Oxymoron",
   "option_c": "Paradox",
   "option_d": "Simile",
   "answer": "D",
   "solution": "The excerpt in the question above is testing students knowledge on figure of speech. Simile is the comparison of two things using 'as' or 'like'. The excerpt compared skin and morning dew using 'like'."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on J.C. De Graft's Sons and Daughters\n\nThe Major issues at hand in the Sons and Daughters play is that",
   "option_a": "Laboratory attendant is trying to act as a nurse",
   "option_b": "The medical doctor is in love with Maanan",
   "option_c": "James sees Awere as a bad influence",
   "option_d": "Lawyer B is trying to Kiss Maanan.",
   "answer": "D",
   "solution": "Most student failed to read, understand and this discuss play among themselves. The lawyer fell in love with Maanan which is not interested in lawyer B's love. Lawyer effort to kiss Maanan became an issue in the play."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on General literacy principles\n\n\nA poet's use of regular rhythm is known as",
   "option_a": "allegory",
   "option_b": "assonance",
   "option_c": "metre",
   "option_d": "onomatopoeia",
   "answer": "C",
   "solution": "Metre is the measurement and arrangement of regular number of stressed and unstressed syllabus within a line. It is determined by rhythm in a poem"
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on Literary Appreciation.\n\n\nThat age is best which the first is.\n\nWhen youth and blood are Warner;\n\nBut being spent, the worse ,\n\nand worst Times still succeed the former.\n\nThe rhyme scheme is",
   "option_a": "abba",
   "option_b": "abab",
   "option_c": "aabb",
   "option_d": "bbaa",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "Rhyme is the language of poetry that is expressed rhythmically. In poem, the similar sound of the last word is arranged as sounds."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on J.C. De Graft's Sons and Daughters\n\n\nThe device used by Aaron in the excerpt below is___________\n\n\n'Now look what we have: a permanent bloom of ugly paper flowers!",
   "option_a": "Rhetorical question",
   "option_b": "Oxymoron",
   "option_c": "Alliteration",
   "option_d": "Euphemism",
   "answer": "B",
   "solution": "The excerpt ended with exclamation mark not a question mark which automatically nullify option A (i.e. Rhetorical question - which is a question that requires no answer). Oxymoron is the answer because it is the placement of two opposite words side by side; paper flower in the excerpt is oxymoron."
 },
 {
   "question": "This question is based on William Shakespeare’s Romeo and Juliet.\n\n\nWhat can you infer about Benvolio based on his interaction with Romeo and parents",
   "option_a": "Benvolio is a troublemaker",
   "option_b": "Benvolio is a cabinet maker",
   "option_c": "Benvolio is kingmaker",
   "option_d": "Benvolio is a peacemaker",
   "answer": "D",
   "solution": "Benvolio is a peacemaker. He is a Montague and Romeo's friend. He attempts to stop the opening fight with the Capulets in the market."
 }
]